A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Rockefeller Boards, Series O FA324
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Institute
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Hideyo Noguchi, 1926-1938 (Box 46, Folder 458)
    Dr. Noguchi's identification of poliomyelitis organism; other discoveries; sketch of his life. His death; tributes; memorials to him in Japan; Japanese plans for biography. Correspondents include Dr. Noguchi, Dr. Simon Flexner, Dr. William H. Welch, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Hideyo Noguchi, 1939-1957 (Box 46, Folder 459)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Presbyterian Hospital Property, 1915-1920 (Box 46, Folder 460)
    Purchase of block between 67th and 68th Streets; use of it as playground. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Simon Flexner, Starr J. Murphy, Thomas M. Debevoise, Henry James, Edric B. Smith, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Presbyterian Hospital Property - Playground, Lenox Hill, 1920-1924 (Box 46, Folder 461)
    Creation of playground area; transactions with Lenox Hill neighborhood association; operation of Lenox Hill settlement house.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Building, 1956-1960 (Box 46, Folder 462)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed $2,500,000 toward cost of social and residential building for faculty and visiting scientists; comments on hall. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Detlev W. Bronk, David Rockefeller.
  - Rockefeller Institute - David Rockefeller, 1950-1956 (Box 46, Folder 463)
    David Rockefeller served as Institute President and Chairman of the Board; problems of Institute; tax and personnel questions. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Detlev W. Bronk, John E. Lockwood, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Rockefeller Institute - David Rockefeller, 1957-1961 (Box 46, Folder 464)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. William H. Welch Correspondence, 1912-1931 (Box 47, Folder 465)
    Dr. Welch's connection with International Congress of Hygiene and Demography; Flexner's biographical note on Welch; Welch's 80th birthday, illness, resignation, death. Correspondents include Dr. William H. Welch, Dr. Simon Flexner, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Senator F. C. Walcott, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. William H. Welch Correspondence, 1932-1941 (Box 47, Folder 466)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Simon Flexner Retirement/Succession of Dr. Herbert S. Gasser, 1935-1936 (Box 47, Folder 467)
    Administrative details in connection with the change. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Franklin C. McLean, Nicholas Murray Butler, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dr. Simon Flexner, Dr. Charles R. Stockard, Henry James, Edric B. Smith.
    31.1A
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Simon Flexner Retirement/Succession of Dr. Herbert S. Gasser - Dr. Flexner Regarding Salary and Pensions, 1935 (Box 47, Folder 468)
    Suggested salary for successor; question of Flexner's status after retirement. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. Simon Flexner, Henry James, Dr. Charles R. Stockard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Simon Flexner Retirement/Succession of Dr. Herbert S. Gasser - Publicity, 1935-1936 (Box 47, Folder 469)
    Policy regarding handling of publicity on Dr. Gasser's appointment. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, T. J. Ross, Harcourt Parrish, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Simon Flexner Retirement/Succession of Dr. Herbert S. Gasser - Dr. Herbert S. Gasser, 1935 (Box 47, Folder 470)
    Research vs. administrative obligations; release from Cornell University. European trip; acceptance of directorship; salary, insurance, pension. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. Herbert S. Gasser, Livingston Farrand, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Henry James.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Simon Flexner Retirement/Succession of Dr. Herbert S. Gasser - Dr. George H. Whipple, 1935 (Box 47, Folder 471)
    Dr. Whipple declines directorship of Institute. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dr. George H. Whipple, Henry James.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Schermerhorn Property - Sale to Institute, 1911-1912 (Box 47, Folder 472)
    Consolidation and purchase of properties. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. conveyed strip of land to Institute. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Dr. Holt, Thomas M. Debevoise, H. W. Nichols, Frederick T. Gates, Charles O. Heydt.
    31.10
  - Rockefeller Institute - Schermerhorn Property - Agreements and Deeds, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., in Account with John D. Rockefeller, 1902-1917 (Box 47, Folder 473)
    Consolidation and purchase of properties. For purchase of Schermerhorn property; includes payment of taxes, property costs and interest. Work papers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Dr. Holt, Thomas M. Debevoise, H. W. Nichols, Frederick T. Gates, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Schermerhorn Property - H. W. Nichols, 1902-1906 (Box 47, Folder 474)
    Early survey and background material leading to property purchase.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Malt Property, 1921-1932 (Box 48, Folder 475)
    Purchase of property from City by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to prevent tannery's use of property; conveyance of property to Institute. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Chauncey Belknap, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. Simon Flexner.
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also 3 oversized items in Room 107, Drawer 21, Folder 91.
  - The Campus of The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Showing Parcels of Land Contributed by the Messrs. Rockefeller (4 maps), 1915-1931 (Drawer B 1)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Malt Property - Avenue A - Bulkhead Lease from New York City, 1921-1924 (Box 48, Folder 476)
    Moving Trinity Coal Company docks; question of industries to be allowed in 67th-64th Street dock area; bulkhead leases. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Alfred E. Smith.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Malt Property - Avenue A - Bulkhead Lease from New York City, 1925-1938 (Box 48, Folder 477)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Malt Property - 63rd Street Dock - East River Esplanade, 1936-1938 (Box 48, Folder 478)
    Plan to extend Exterior Street and Esplanade; coal docks moved again; evolution of plan into East River Drive.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Avenue A Apartments, 1922-1939 (Box 48, Folder 479)
    Management of apartments built for staff of Institute. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Sale of Princeton Property, 1947-1952 (Box 48, Folder 480)
    Attempts to sell property. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. Lindsley F. Kimball.
    31.13A
  - Rockefeller Institute - Sale of Princeton Property, 1950 (Box 48, Folder 0480A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Sale of New Jersey Property to Princeton, 1950-1951 (Box 48, Folder 481)
    Price, agreement to sell; sale of tools to Princeton; publicity. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. Lindsley F. Kimball, John E. Lockwood, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    31.13B
  - Rockefeller Institute - Sale of New Jersey Property to Princeton, 1950-1951 (Box 48, Folder 0481A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - New Building and Alteration Program, 1949-1950 (Box 48, Folder 482)
    Cost estimates and agreements with contractors. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John Lockwood.
    31.14
  - Rockefeller Institute - Rutherford Estate Fund, 1913-1940 (Box 48, Folder 483)
    Probation of will; management of fund. Correspondents include Lefferts M. Dashiell, Thomas M. Debevoise, Starr J. Murphy.
    31.2
  - Rockefeller Institute - Transfer of East 68th-69th Street Block, 1933-1946 (Box 48, Folder 484)
    Transfer of Memorial Hospital property from Institute; application for tax exemption; opinion regarding title; disposition of land. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
    31.3
  - Rockefeller Institute - Transfer of East 68th-69th Street Block - Use of Property for Playground, 1935 (Box 48, Folder 485)
    City used property for a playground prior to transfer to hospital.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Transfer of East 68th-69th Street Block - Use of Property - Avenue A and 66th Street, 1903-1912 (Box 49, Folder 486)
    Plot used for playground in summer; proposed purchase of plot by City from Institute.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Department of Animal Pathology, 1914-1915 (Box 49, Folder 487)
    Question of whether state legislature can limit Institute's choice of location; special charter in New Jersey. Practice on animals in New Jersey; records of Executive Committee of Scientific Directors regarding farm management. Proposals for development of farm; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift. Correspondents include Roger S. Greene, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. Simon Flexner, Frederick T. Gates, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Department of Animal Pathology - Dr. Theobald Smith, 1914-1915 (Box 49, Folder 488)
    Preliminary study of Smith's recommendation that department be established; Dr. Smith selected as director.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Department of Animal Pathology - Clyde Farm, 1907-1914 (Box 49, Folder 489)
    Plans and reasons for purchasing farm; subsequent sale to the Rubins; Rubins' financial difficulties.
    31.3A
    See also 1 blueprint in Room 107, Drawer 21, Folder 91.
  - Map Showing Lands of J.D. Greene, Esq.- South Brunswick, Middlesex Co., NJ, Surveyed and Drawn by C.S. Sincerbeaux, Princeton, NJ, 1915 January; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 1, Folder 91)
    Box 49, Folder 489
  - Rockefeller Institute - Department of Animal Pathology - Princeton Property, 1915-1919 (Box 49, Folder 490)
    Negotiations in purchasing land; price; crop season; indemnification. Construction, planning, development of work at Princeton; labor problems. Question of joining farm cooperative association. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Edric B. Smith, J. J. Hill.
    31.3B
  - Rockefeller Institute - Department of Animal Pathology - Princeton Property - March 26, 1914 Pledge, 1914-1917 (Box 49, Folder 491)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift to found department, $1,000,000; Mr. Hill's offer of gift to help combat hog cholera. Correspondents include J. J. Hill, Henry James, Starr J. Murphy.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Finance Committee, 1937 (Box 49, Folder 492)
    Use of reserve funds; sums realized from sales of securities; financial prospects of investments and prospective investments. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    31.4
  - Rockefeller Institute - Finance Committee, 1949-1958 (Box 49, Folder 0492A)
    Use of reserve funds; sums realized from sales of securities; financial prospects of investments and prospective investments. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Edward Robinson.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Finance Committee - Salaries, 1915-1922 (Box 49, Folder 493)
    Controversy over investigation of adequacy of wages; comparative data on wages. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Simon Flexner.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Finance Committee - Purchases and Sales, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 494)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Finance Committee - Statements, 1948, 1954 (Box 49, Folder 495)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1901-1908 (Box 49, Folder 496)
    June 14, 1901 gift of $200,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
    31.5
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1907-1911 (Box 49, Folder 497)
    June 24, 1902 pledge of $1,000,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1907-1911 (Box 49, Folder 498)
    November 11, 1907 gift of $2,600,000. June 30, 1910 gift of $3,641,236.48. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1907-1910 (Box 49, Folder 499)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1908-1910 (Box 49, Folder 500)
    June 22, 1908 gift of $500,000. January 12, 1910 gift of $120,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1908-1910 (Box 49, Folder 501)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1911 (Box 49, Folder 502)
    June 5, 1911 gift of $924,707.63. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1911 (Box 49, Folder 503)
    June 5, 1911 gift of $2,000,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1911 (Box 49, Folder 504)
    November 20, 1911 gift of $225,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1912 (Box 49, Folder 505)
    June 20, 1912 gift of $1,500,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1913 (Box 49, Folder 506)
    May 22, 1913 gift of $500,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1914 (Box 49, Folder 507)
    March 26, 1914 gift of $1,000,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1914-1916 (Box 49, Folder 508)
    June 24, 1914 gift of $2,500,000. April 17, 1915 gift of $350,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1915 (Box 49, Folder 509)
    Western Pacific Bonds exchange. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1915-1916 (Box 49, Folder 510)
    December 29, 1915 gift of $1,000,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1916 (Box 49, Folder 511)
    February 7, 1916 gift of $1,000,000. October 3, 1916 gift of $24,501.69. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1917 (Box 49, Folder 512)
    March 1917. $200,000 from Rockefeller Foundation for Dr. Alexis Carrel. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1917 (Box 50, Folder 513)
    June 17 gift of $2,000,000 from Rockefeller Foundation. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1919-1920 (Box 50, Folder 514)
    April 30, 1919 gift of $10,000,000. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1920 (Box 50, Folder 515)
    December 15, 1920. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1921 (Box 50, Folder 516)
    April 5, 1921. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1926-1933 (Box 50, Folder 517)
    July 8, 1926. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts, 1926-1928 (Box 50, Folder 518)
    August 2, 1926. Gifts from the Rockefeller family, General Education Board, and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Henry James, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Gifts and Funds, 1914-1971 (Box 50, Folder 519)
    Summary reports of early gifts; correspondence regarding later gifts. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Rockefeller Institute - History of Institute, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 520)
    Provision for a committee to prepare a history; description of organization, establishment, functioning and financing of Institute; Richardson survey, early history of decision to establish Institute in New York City; question of independence vs. university connection. Correspondents include Dr. William H. Welch, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    31.6
  - Rockefeller Institute - History of Institute, 1948-1966 (Box 50, Folder 521)
  - Rockefeller Institute - History of Institute, 1954-1960 (Box 50, Folder 0521A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Pensions, 1912-1933 (Box 50, Folder 522)
    Pension system as organized in 1913 and subsequently revised. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Henry James, Roger S. Greene, Trevor Arnett.
    31.7
  - Rockefeller Institute - Pensions, 1934-1938 (Box 50, Folder 523)
    Pension system as organized in 1913 and subsequently revised. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas M. Debevoise, Henry James, Trevor Arnett, Chauncey Belknap, Edric B. Smith.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Pensions, 1939-1956 (Box 50, Folder 524)
    Pension system as organized in 1913 and subsequently revised. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas M. Debevoise, Henry James, Chauncey Belknap, Dr. Herbert S. Gasser, Edric B. Smith, Dr. Alfred E. Cohn.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Pensions - Dr. Alexis Carrel's Retirement, 1938-1940 (Box 51, Folder 525)
    Retirement-at-65 rule enforced against Dr. Alexis Carrel, who didn't wish to retire yet.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Reports, 1956-1961 (Box 51, Folder 526)
    Reports by business managers and scientific directors.
    31.8
  - Rockefeller Institute - Rockefeller Institute Quarterly, 1957-1960 (Box 51, Folder 527)
    31.81
  - Rockefeller Institute - Trustees, 1908-1958 (Box 51, Folder 528)
    Resignations, deaths, replacements in various committees and boards; rules governing powers of trustees. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, Simon Flexner, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    31.9
  - Rockefeller Institute - Trustees, 1939-1958 (Box 51, Folder 0528A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Trustees - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Resignation from Presidency, 1950-1951 (Box 51, Folder 529)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. resigned, April 17, 1950. David Rockefeller becomes third president of the Institute. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Dr. Herbert S. Gasser.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Trustees - Elections and Resignations, 1926-1949 (Box 51, Folder 530)
    Elections and resignations of trustees and scientific directors. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Trustees - Elections and Resignations, 1942-1949 (Box 51, Folder 0530A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Trustees - Elections and Resignations, 1950-1958 (Box 51, Folder 531)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Trustees - Rules and Amendments, 1910-1924 (Box 51, Folder 532)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Committee on Buildings and Grounds, 1956-1958 (Box 51, Folder 533)
    31.91
  - Rockefeller Institute - Special Committee on Appraisal and Succession, 1951-February 1952 (Box 51, Folder 534)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Special Committee on Appraisal and Succession, March 1952-1967 (Box 51, Folder 535)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Frederick T. Gates Correspondence, 1907-1910 (Box 52, Folder 536)
    Technical reprints; clippings regarding Institute; administrative matters. Gifts; personal correspondence with Institute members. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, Simon Flexner.
    31.92
  - Rockefeller Institute - Frederick T. Gates Correspondence, 1911-1924 (Box 52, Folder 537)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Anti-Vivisection, 1908-1921 (Box 52, Folder 538)
    Entreaties by private individuals and groups; attempts at restrictive legislation. Correspondents include Simon Flexner, Starr J. Murphy, Dr. Alexis Carrel.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Newspaper Articles, 1901-1914 (Box 52, Folder 539)
    Articles on John D. Rockefeller's gifts and plans for the Institute.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Miscellaneous Memos Regarding Cost of Properties, 1907 (Box 52, Folder 540)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Hospital, 1906-1908 (Box 52, Folder 541)
    Decision to add hospital to Institute; estimates, data on costs, John D. Rockefeller's gift; conveyance of property and acquisition of additional land; outside gifts; John D. Rockefeller pledge to defray salaries. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick T. Gates, Simon Flexner.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Hospital, 1909-1916 (Box 52, Folder 542)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Hospital - Proposed Gift of 1910, 1907, 1910 (Box 52, Folder 543)
    Reorganization; gift; authorization for transfer of funds.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Campus Map, circa 1931 (Box F 091, Folder 1)
    "The Campus of The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Showing Parcels of Land Contributed by the Messrs. Rockefeller as of 1931."
    Handwritten on front: 1 in a circle. Handwritten on verso: Harold Oakhill, 5/85. Four circular Velcro pieces adhered to the back of the map in the corners.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Special arrangements may be necessary in order to view this item. Item may be restricted due to preservation concerns.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Malt Property, 1922 (Box F 091, Folder 2)